The following content is provided under a Creative
Commons license.
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
offer high quality educational resources for free.
To make a donation or view additional materials from
hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare at
ocw.mit.edu.
OK, most everyone's here.
We're still going to take a few minutes to wait for the
last few people to show up.
I don't have a ton of announcements, but if you
looked at the syllabus, you might notice that there are a
couple days where we have, I think we've got TBD as the
topic, like TB-Determined.
What I'd like to do is just take a quick poll from you all.
Is there anything that you are interested in learning about
in the creation of video games that you either, we
haven't talked about it in class yet, maybe we've talked
about it, but not fully?
You've looked at the syllabus and it's not there on the
syllabus, or it's something that you think is going to be
directly useful for the games that you're working on
right now.
So just putting that out there, if there's any topics you
might want to talk about, learn about, let me know.
Yes?
Okay, so yeah, cool.
So what people do in the industry?
Cool, you are in luck.
On December 1st and 3rd, on the first we're having a
business and games panel, so two independent developers in
the area are going to come by and talk about how they started
their companies, what do they do, what's their daily life,
things like that.
And then another one following that is the community
manager for Firehose Games.
Sean Baptiste is going to talk to us about how do they get
their games out in the world, and how do they get people to
play their games, and how do they engage their fan base,
and how do they even just create a fan base in general.
So that's not on the syllabus, but that will be, we will be
doing that.
Any other topics?
Okay, I want to ask this again in a couple of weeks in case
something pops up, because you probably haven't done a lot of
technical things with your game engines yet.
So if there's anything gaming specific that you might want to
know about, either let us know through the video game
bosses email address, or let us know a class, yeah.
Who would be giving you the answers, like if it's open to,
can you get people?
I can get people, so I can get people who are local.
We've got connections to local industry.
We've got connections to the people who make the tools,
in some cases, depending on the tool.
That's kind of why I'm asking now, because it gives me time to
find new, to fill new gaps.
Also, it might be something that we can talk to.
So if there's anything design related that you think is useful
for your games that we haven't talked about yet, and you don't
get on the schedule, let us know.
If there's anything technical related, Drew can come up and
say something.
The other thing we can do is, if there's anything that you
want to do, or if you want to set up office hours in class
to talk about a certain topic for your game, specifically
technical issues, technical questions, that's what Drew is
here for, to come and talk with your group as a whole, or
just individual members of your group to talk about the
issues that you have.
So we can do that during class, during our schedule, one
and a half to two hour work in class periods, or you can set
up office hours with them.
OK, I'll just give people a couple more minutes.
The attendance sheet is moving around.
So is everybody sitting with their teams right now?
Does it look like?
Can we just show, I'm going to go across and just kind of try
to figure out which of these teams are.
So this is the SNAP team.
Is everyone here?
Two, OK.
Which team, this is forecast-based futures over
here, right?
How far do you go?
John, are you in this team, or are you in the next team?
Cool, all right.
Next team over, which team are you?
Collara?
No.
You're a Collara team?
Were you the Island group?
Animal Crossing one, cool.
And then in the front here, we've got Heat Wave, and in the
back, it's the other Collara group.
OK, I did not get a chance to play your game.
But I will, eventually.
I'm cool.
So there's going to be a little bit of an
interactivity in the talk.
I've given this talk before.
I rewrote the lectures, and I haven't given it since I
rewrote the lecture, so we'll see how it goes.
They're my backup to let me know if I forgot anything.
There will be some reading on this that I'm going to put
into Stellar.
So if you are interested in the topic, if you have more
interest in the topic and you want to read the reading, I
highly recommend it, especially if you think you're
going to be in a leadership position in the future, or
any kind of managerial position, or you're interested in
just psychology and how people talk to each other and work
together.
So our three main topics.
This will actually be pretty quick on this lecture.
We're going to do a really quick review of Agile.
We're going to talk about team dynamics.
And then we're going to talk about how do distributed
Agile teams perform?
So what are some of the best practices they have for
performing?
And then you're going to work in class.
And you'll have at least two hours to work in class today,
if not a little bit more than that.
So Agile processes.
If you forget everything in this class, you end the class,
you got into the real world, and somebody asks you, what
is Agile?
I hope you remember this part.
Iterative development.
Does anybody consider what they're doing iterative
development on their projects right now?
Are you working in short periods of time so you've broken up
your time into small sprints?
Are you doing all?
You can't really read it that well in the slide.
But are you within that short period of time designing what
you're going to work on, planning how it's going to
work, doing it, and then testing it, evaluating the test
and changing?
Are you doing all of that within one week or two week
cycle?
Raise your hands, yay?
So yes, raise your hands.
No, raise your hands.
It's OK if you say no.
OK.
If you're doing something that looks like this, then great.
And as remember, Agile, in particular, scrum processes,
they're based on these three pillars that Sarah talked
about when we first brought this up.
So the pillar of transparency, and what we mean by
transparency there, we really just
mean a common nomenclature.
To be honest, I don't care what you call the things that you
use as part of your process in your team.
So long as everyone within the team knows what it is, so long
as whoever you're submitting those processes to also know
who it is.
So we're not acting as your product owners in the class.
But if you had a product owner, they should also know what
you're calling things, what you're calling your product
backlog, what you're calling a task, how you're estimating,
and how you're doing your processes.
So everyone on the team should know it, not just in a more
traditional manner, a project manager knowing what all the
processes are.
There's a number of inspection that's going on.
So through the process, you are taking a look at all the
artifacts you created, so those backlog items, task lists,
things like that that you're creating during the process.
You're inspecting it, and in particular, you're inspecting
it during meetings.
So you're taking a look at what you've done in a meeting and
talking about it.
So you're not just doing a process.
You're doing a process, and you're talking about it, and
you're actively thinking about the process.
And then you're adapting.
So based on evidence, based on needs, changes in needs, you
are changing that process.
Again, if you're doing any one of these three things, you're
doing process as well, and you're doing some form of
agile-like process.
Another thing I hope you take from the class.
The agile manifesto, it is a manifesto.
It is an idea.
It is something that has some political weight behind it
that is saying, this is the way to do things.
This is the right way to do things.
But it's actually more vague than that.
It's really just saying, here are some four key things that
we feel are more important than other four key things.
And today, we're going to focus.
So the first item is individuals and interactions
over processes and tools.
So we've been talking to you a lot about process and tools
for the first part of the semester.
Now we're going to talk about individuals and interactions
between individuals.
So your team members.
All right.
What's a team?
Anybody give me a working definition for what you'd
call a team?
What'd you say?
A bunch of puppies.
Is it a group of people?
Is it just a group of people?
A group of people working toward a common purpose.
Anything else?
So it's a collection of individuals.
So it's a group of people.
They're working toward a common purpose.
They have shared responsibility for common outcomes.
If one of those puppies trips, that stick
goes in another puppy's mouth, and it hurts a lot.
So I want you to keep that in mind.
Shared responsibility, common purpose, common outcome.
All right.
So teams evolve over time.
And the little bit of research I'm going to talk about
actually comes from studying group behaviors.
But this is all from about the 1960s and on up.
And around the 2000s, and I'll post this reading up,
it was proven, or there was some studies showing that this
actually works for teams.
This does work for people who have a common goal.
But as you get a bunch of people together,
and you get a small group of people together,
and in our terms, we're calling a small group of people
eight to 10 people, maybe a little bit bigger,
but about 10 people total.
They're going to evolve based on those interpersonal
relationships, so how they know each other,
what they talk about, how they talk about,
and their task behaviors.
So we're going to be talking about not the tasks that you
are doing in your teams, but the behaviors surrounding
the tasks that you're doing it.
So if you are working on a task, if you are doing some coding,
how are you coding?
Or who are you coding with?
How are you talking to other people about what you're coding?
And you can apply that to any other tasks
that you're doing in your teams.
There's a lot of different theories.
Actually, Wikipedia is a pretty good nutshell
of what are all the different kinds of theories
and how different kind of models we
can use to describe how groups talk to each other
and how groups evolve, but they all
come down to these common things.
There's a period of getting to know each other.
There's a period of experiencing conflict,
and there's both positive and negative conflict
when you're talking with each other.
Your roles shift based on changing knowledge
and changing experience, and hopefully at some point,
there's some kind of consensus.
There's some kind of moving forward.
Decisions happen here.
The point is, though, what kind of decisions get made?
Are they effective decisions?
Or are they ineffective, unproven?
They get made because you just have to make them
and you have to move on.
And what we're hoping is that by analyzing how your teams work,
you can then move towards having some effective decision
making.
So the model that we're going to talk about
is Tuckman's model from 65.
It's got four phases, forming, norming, storming, performing.
It's very cutesy.
It's used in training sessions a lot.
It can just be something that you can just spit out and say.
And someone says, oh, you're smart.
You know that model.
But maybe you don't know everything behind it.
I might be more in the, you're smart,
but maybe you don't know more everything behind it.
I'm still learning about how this works.
But each phase has items you can identify.
And more useful for us is this is a model
you can use to figure out where your team is right now.
What phase are you in?
So you can then make decisions about where you need to go
and how you need to work together better.
So the forming phase of it.
This is when you first start getting together.
Everyone wants to be friendly.
Everyone wants to get along, to be accepted with each other.
There might be some serious problems from the get-go,
but they're usually avoided.
And the team learns about challenges and goals.
But not much gets done.
There's no real task completion going on in the stage.
Is that everybody's seen this,
when you think about your previous teams,
you've been in this stage, right?
When you first got together.
So project two, project three.
I'm gonna ask you some questions about project two
and three as we go forward.
All right, that's a happy stage.
Then storming happens.
People are able to express discontent.
There actually might have been discontents in phase one,
but it actually wasn't being expressed in some form.
In phase two, it's being expressed.
But how it's being expressed can be kind of different.
So it could be someone actively saying,
no, you're wrong, that's stupid.
It could be someone not talking,
but they're feeling the same thing
and they're thinking about the same thing.
It's the same kind of discontent that happened.
Opinions tend to get challenged.
It can be contentious, it can be unpleasant.
In order to advance past this stage,
what your team really needs is tolerance and patience.
I'm just gonna get through it.
But even more important,
you need to establish lines of trust
and open communication to get through the stage.
And this is what we've been doing
for the past first of the semester, is creating processes.
We've been giving you some tools that you can use,
then you can then create those processes in your teams.
So just a quick hand raise from teams.
Does anybody think that they are in this stage right now?
Do you think in your team you are currently,
you're expressing discontent, you are creating processes,
you don't have processes yet,
but you're figuring out what your processes might be?
Maybe, what do you say?
You're not sure?
Okay, all right.
Next up, norming.
So this is where you have those processes.
Individuals start giving up their own ideas and goals.
You're actually moving towards a team goal right now.
And people are starting to take responsibility
and rules are established.
Okay, comparing storming to norming,
raise your hands if you think your team is in norming
right now.
Okay, yeah.
All right, now raise your hands
if you think your team is in storming right now.
Okay.
All right, so, is anybody performing?
Are you functioning as a unit efficiently?
Are your team members already autonomous?
Is dissent expected and addressed right now?
This is where you want to get to.
You probably aren't this far yet.
My bet's you're probably somewhere
in the storming area things,
maybe getting close to the norming area things.
Basically, you're still talking to each other,
you're still trying to figure out
what are the different ways of communicating with each other.
What are the different processes and rules you might have?
And you might not get this far in class.
By the end of the semester, you might not be
fully efficient by the end of the semester.
Fully efficient by the end of the class, and that's okay.
But if you are, it's kind of cool.
So, the model in practice tends to be, it's non-linear.
It gets talked about and it was originally established
as you go from here to here to here to here.
You go through the phases, at the end of the thing,
you're done, your team's awesome, go you.
We actually see in process is that teams tend to,
they get in the forming, they go in the circle,
where they go from having some issues,
figuring out how to deal with those issues,
establish some rules, all right,
we're doing really well again, new challenge comes up,
we're back into storming, we've put ourselves in a position
where we don't know how to talk to each other,
or we don't know how to communicate with each other.
So, there's some problems with the model.
This is really a descriptive model.
It's a tool for us to use to see how things are going.
It's basically a way to evaluate symptoms,
but there's no triggers in the model.
We don't know when those things happen.
When does your team switch from storming to norming?
So this is what I'd like you to do in your teams,
just take a couple minutes, talk about your previous teams
you've been on, talk about the team you're on now.
When do you think your team would move from stage to stage,
and how could a team move intentionally?
So, and in particular,
think about that storming to norming part of it.
So what is it going to take for your team right now,
or what happened in your team right now,
to go from we are having some difficulty talking
with each other, we have a bunch of opinions,
to we're on the same page?
Take three minutes.
Just one thing I want to chime in.
There's a very, very good chance
that your team actually is still in forming stage,
and one of the reasons why no one,
like a very few of you might have put up your hands
that you don't actually want to express dissent,
which is exactly the situation
that you get in the forming stage.
You know, it is uncomfortable,
but hopefully you can logically see the benefits
of being in a team where you can talk about
the things that you disagree with, right?
So, it's possible that you are still in forming,
and it's good to identify your teams as,
okay, this is normal evolution of a team,
and that's where our team is at right now.
So talk about it among your team.
So take three minutes, just talking to your teams,
and then I'm gonna ask you some questions when we're done.
Okay, so, each group, give me something you talked about,
about what are the triggers,
what are the things you saw as you moved?
Just let me know which phases you're talking about.
So, go ahead.
Okay.
How do you know?
Or what caused that, what caused you to get there,
do you think?
Before the game, we had a story out,
and that was what we had to go through, sorry.
The reason that everything that we had to go through,
we're closer to forming now is because we just,
it's like, that's the end of the big amount of information
and what our team has done, much faster.
Okay.
Now let me get up to the front end for the forming,
and probably in the starting, yeah.
You guys are still working on the design decisions.
All right, so it's big decisions.
How big are those two teams?
Four and four, okay.
Is this somebody else?
Next.
A trigger that you saw that made you go
from one stage to the other.
I think we're also, as a team,
we're moving from story to learning.
And part of that, a trigger was solidifying our game,
or working on solidifying our game idea,
because at this point, while we all recognize
that we're one of the games in team,
we all have different ideas of what this game should be,
and as we are solidifying our game,
we're also getting ourselves in line
with what we're actually doing and how we're gonna make it.
Okay.
So do you think that the task of solidifying the game idea
is helping you, because there's this big decision
you have to make, is that helping you move,
like work as a team?
It's not getting in your way?
I think it's the fact that, like, as we're doing this,
we have a lot of, we definitely have to sort of conflict
in our team, where people work and start to have
different ideas and trying to work through it.
And at first, we weren't doing the best job
of getting those ideas and working through them,
but I see that now we're doing a much better job
while we're standing each other and seeing how it fits
into the bigger picture.
Okay, cool.
Next team.
A triggering moment that you saw in this team
or previous teams.
So we had a bigger college team at first,
and I think that having the decision to split up
was a way that help us jump down from it to storm it,
because ideas you sort of start to get,
are slowly to get to your ideas,
so they're conflicting ideas in terms of where our games go
in the previous storm session.
So it's basically just,
it's reducing the number of opinions, right?
Really, right?
And that was killing three people.
So with our game, I think getting Mr. Norming was really,
they talked about assigning tasks,
but also just the accountability aspect,
because instead of spending time arguing,
we already kind of have a designated person
or a couple of people who are accountable
for different things, which allows us to just kind of,
not argue in a deeper way.
So that's, like certain people have different,
they own some sub-taskers, own sub-rolls.
Okay, cool.
In the back, what do you think?
So I guess what's got us over to storming
was meeting together as a team to make design decisions,
or sort of like what has been said there.
I think that the next step for bringing us over to storming
would be like actually getting everyone
to participate in design decisions,
because people have both not shown up
and not particularly shown interest in getting things going.
So getting everyone on board, even, is specific.
All right, so that's a big one.
That's a huge difficulty with,
especially with student projects.
You've got all these other things going on around you.
Do you think you need everyone to contribute to the design,
or do you need everyone to be on board with the design?
So I understand like some people just are less interested
in having deep discussions about the design of the game,
but getting everyone to both be aware
and willing to participate when they need to.
Okay, because yeah, there's important conversations
being done that if they're not there when it happens,
they're not gonna know where the status of the game is.
Yeah, and they just need to be willing to participate.
If they're not there, take the step of,
oh, what'd you guys talk about?
I'm interested in knowing how long to.
Okay, cool.
Thank you for that lead,
because that gets us to our next stage.
So we're talking kind of,
I think we find ourselves talking a lot
about the product that we're making.
It's just easier.
It's the thing, it's that hard evident,
like that hard thing you can see,
like it's being made, it's being done.
We can play it.
That means we're probably doing something right,
but it's still very difficult still to talk about the people.
Although I saw being talking with the people a little bit here,
especially with accountability in this one, it was good.
Cool.
So that brings you to the next topic.
Teams are composed of individuals,
and each person on your team
is gonna have a lot of different factors
affecting what they do, how they do it, when they do it.
I can't give you the magic formula to get them motivated.
What I can do is show you some of the different ways
that you can then try to either understand
the people you're with,
understand the people on your team,
or find things to talk to them about.
You might notice a number of these things.
So to get someone who's motivated,
someone who's gonna be able to participate,
think about all these things.
Think about personal development.
So you're in a class,
you were here hopefully because you want to learn.
You want to learn a new skill, you want to try a new skill.
Everyone wants to learn a new skill.
There might be a skill that they wanna work on on your team.
And I think we've talked about that in the past
when we were talking about the vision statement
and people putting down why they're involved on the team
and why they're involved on this project.
So being aware of that
and constantly coming back to that for each person,
especially if you have someone on your team
who is just not participating
and you need to figure out how to engage them.
Think about the skills that they wanna bring to the table,
the skills they're trying to practice.
When it comes to motivation,
it largely comes down to intrinsic or extrinsic.
The extrinsic might be the grade they're gonna get,
but it's really difficult to really hone in on that
because the grade's shared between your groups.
So that might not be the place to look at.
Try to take a look at the intrinsic things.
What are the things that,
if they were enthusiast,
if they had enthusiasms about the project at some point,
try to remember what that was.
Ask somebody else on your team what that might have been.
See if you can bring that enthusiasm back into the project.
Morale or self-worth, there's been some research that shows
that the reason why people work well on teams
and the reason why we want to work on teams
is because it brings us self-worth.
There is, and in particular,
there's some self-awareness that can happen
by being on a team and getting,
and actually kinda links a little bit to extrinsic rewards,
by getting rewarded, getting feedback on my performance
is gonna help me do better.
Empowerment, giving ownership.
So raise your hands if your team uses assigning tasks
or taking tasks.
So assigning tasks, raise your hand.
If your team assigns tasks to individuals.
That team?
Kinda?
Yeah?
You assign, so there's one person on your team
that says you are going to do this?
All right.
Has anybody tried ownership
where someone takes a task from a set of tasks
that are available?
Little?
When does that work?
When does ownership work?
It will be forwarded, yeah.
What's that?
Some people are e-reporting,
they're interested in what we're doing.
So there's some of those other things,
that there's some enthusiasm over it.
Yeah?
It's usually like a while before the deadline, too.
So I go like, can you hear your deadline?
Okay, cool.
So yeah, yeah.
Yeah, you can run into problems if you say
like who's gonna do this and I'll be volunteers.
Yeah.
I'm making sure that it's good if you can volunteer
for tasks that they're enthusiastic about,
but then if nobody will volunteer to do something
that needs to be done and so on,
I'm just gonna say, okay, you're gonna do this.
Absolutely.
I feel like I'm in a hybrid environment.
Okay.
So where does it, yeah, go ahead.
Yeah, and I think also it depends on if
everyone on the team is willing to purchase ownership,
or if it's like only some schools,
because that also creates a different dynamic.
Absolutely.
So there's some?
Some people who are like,
do you think you can do this with the other non-students?
Like, do some of them need to start a certain task?
Are they something that's like kind of like
at the beginning after the book is serviced
and then like the task that I left
and then it's like sort of like that.
Okay.
So at the beginning,
everybody takes on tasks and at the end,
when you have the leftovers, they get assigned.
Yeah, Matt?
One of the biggest problems,
I think of this is that when you're not competing
on how it's beginning or working on it,
especially if it's really easy to become a lot of other work,
then things can kind of stall you
because you're helping develop your own games,
you're helping you have to be passive in order to do it.
So it might not, yeah,
so you might not actually have ownership.
It might look like you had ownership.
There was the evidence of ownership
in that someone said, okay, I'll take that task,
but there's no follow through, there's no commitment.
And that gets to the next one, commitment.
The best way to have commitment on your team
is for one person to be committed,
to express that commitment, to express that loyalty
for everyone else to see that loyalty
and see that commitment.
And then hopefully they pick up the ball and they're like,
okay, I'm gonna be committed too.
If that second person doesn't do that, pick it up,
then the chain, it doesn't travel through the chain,
it just doesn't happen.
Even though that one person went out of the way
to show that kind of sacrifice,
it just didn't get picked up.
So maybe think about, do you see that chain happening
on your teams?
Do you see it breaking?
Can you identify where that breaking point is?
And can you think about ways to fix that?
Trust is a big one.
How many, so raise your hands
if you have worked with the majority of the people
on your team before, in some fashion,
this class or other classes.
You feel like you know your teammates.
Like raise your hands if you feel like
you really know your teammates, you've worked with them before.
Hi, if you really think so.
So one, two, maybe.
One, two, three.
So think about how well you know each other.
Think about ways you can figure out
how you can know each other better.
Social interactions, going out to coffee,
going out for lunch, things like that.
Is there something that you can do
that will help that kind of thing happen?
And then here's the big one, this is the MIT One Stress.
And stress tends to be the negative.
It can be positive in that it's the end of the project
and it's due and you just need to get things done.
And that can lead to crunch,
but then there's also the huge negative aspect of stress.
And that's very much an external factor for the most part.
It could be an internal factor.
If stress is in it, if there's some stress
being caused by internal things going on with your team,
it's likely related to one of the ones above it.
So one way to think about these three,
one, two, three, seven things.
You can think of them as in terms of
the desire ability to learn new skills
or the desire ability to take on a task.
So if you're trying to come up with strategies
with your team on how to solve some of these problems,
think of it in those two terms.
All right.
So how do distributed teams perform?
So what do I mean by distributed?
What is a distributed team?
Yeah?
Yeah, or just everyone's all over the place.
It could mean that you are in Singapore
and someone else is in Ohio.
You could be separated by time zones, by oceans.
By, and really, I think that might be
East Campus in the Gregor maybe.
It could just be through distance.
It could be through your schools.
It could be through your departments,
your majors, whatnot.
There's some kind of boundaries going on between people.
In this case, it's largely time.
It's basically, some people can work during some hours.
Some people can't work during those hours.
So what have you done so far to fix that?
Think back on some of the postmortems you've given us.
What are some of the strategies you've already used
and seen used to figure out how to work
in across different time periods?
Yeah?
Well, right now, we're using a Slack,
which is pretty helpful.
What's it called?
Slack.
It's like, Clodoc.
It's like what?
Clodoc?
What's that?
It's group instant messaging.
Yay!
And it keeps track of all our song tasks.
And also, a few more people.
Cool.
Anybody else using a group I am or an IRC chat?
Yeah?
Do you use something called Gitter?
Or do you use, like, a chat and pie
because of your github?
Cool.
Are they just black on the internet or a lot of the github?
I think so, yeah.
Cool.
Okay.
It's great when it can hook up to things
and it works with your workflow.
It's also just great to have this period.
If you don't use any of those,
maybe think about Skype.
Any other things people use?
Yeah?
Um, just, in my experience, like,
if, let's say we're walking on something
and all of a sudden you just have to add a point,
it would be good to, like, keep the whole thing
informed about the progress that's happening on the branch.
So we usually, like, use Google, just Google it out,
explaining exactly what you have done so far.
So reporting.
I remember some people had issues with email
on previous teams.
Is anybody still using email as a primary means
of communication on your team?
How's it working for you, so far?
I think I'm still at this point yet.
Yeah.
I think we started talking about, you know,
the software store so we don't have to do everything.
Yep.
Are those emails gonna be archived and viewable
by everyone at a later date?
It's a good idea.
Yeah.
And I think that's why we tend to think about group IAMs
and particularly, um, Phillip likes IRC.
For that very reason, certain IRC servers
will keep an archive for you on other kinds
of group where we'll do that, too,
but they tend to be pricey.
Has anybody started using Trello on your teams yet?
Yeah.
Are you using it as a communication method
or as a recording of things?
Okay.
Anybody using that as a communication method at all?
Trying that out?
Okay.
Cause I think it can do email notifications
and things like that when things change,
assigning members to tasks, stuff like that.
Cool.
All right.
So again, we got talking into tools.
What other things can we do?
So another paper that is gonna be on Stellar,
if you wanna look at it, was basically a survey
of distributed teams using answer processes
and giving up some best practices
of what worked best for them.
And I was nice.
I'm just giving you the summary of that.
So one thing they noticed is having a one team mindset
was the thing that got them through
working together as a group.
What do we mean by one team?
That the group identifies,
well, firstly, identifies as a team,
like what we talked about before.
They all have a goal that they're going towards.
They all identify as going towards that goal.
They don't identify as just as an individual group.
But that's actually a major part of their identity.
And for them, it's because that's their 40 hour,
80 hour, 120 hour workdays or work weeks.
Something I think you're gonna have an issue with
because you're working smaller periods of time.
But what they're able to do,
the way they're able to do that
is they've got these frequent team interactions.
And actually, when they're working for a long period of time,
there are people who are working on their own
in their home or their home office with another team.
That's very far away.
And yet these teams still do a daily standup.
Does anybody here do a daily standup
on their teams right now?
So what they're doing is they're going on video.
They're talking to each other for a very short period of time
about what they've done, what they're going to do,
what's in their way.
The cool thing with daily standups
and why they think this works for them,
it goes back to those seven items I listed about
how do you get people engaged on a team?
It shows commitment.
The fact that there are some people,
that there are people who are showing up to meetings.
There is some kind of personal sacrifice.
Some people are meeting at a very strange hour of the day
that they're not normally going to meet.
And they're doing that because of the team.
They're sacrificing something personal for the team.
Everyone else on the team sees that.
They see that kind of commitment.
They feel like they need to reflect that back themselves.
Also trust.
And in this particular case,
it's the trust of not letting meetings take too long.
These daily standups really should only take 10 minutes.
An effective team can do it in five.
Effective 10-person team, 30 seconds each go.
Everyone says what they've done.
Everyone sees it with other's faces.
The great thing about seeing each other's faces
is you can see what stage of fear and anxiety they're in.
Then you can then talk to them later
and have some other personal interactions with them.
The other thing they do is they do co-located work.
They've got money sometimes,
so they're flying people back and forth.
But again, they're also doing co-located work
by doing things, having Skype always on in the background
while they're working together.
But they're not doing it the entire time.
They can't afford that.
So one thing you can do is to schedule your co-located time
at the beginning of the project,
which is basically what we've been doing in class
for the past few weeks,
identifying important milestones
and making sure you've scheduled a co-located period
during that milestone,
right before that milestone is gonna help you greatly,
doing Instric teams and doing video chat.
And here's a big one we haven't talked about in class so much,
but I get the impression that some of you
might be interested in this kind of thing, having coaches.
So we've already seen some of the teams
have a dedicated scrum master or producer.
Think about having a dedicated coach.
So someone who's on your team,
who is there to cultivate team spirit,
they're gonna emphasize the importance of one team.
They could be your scrum master or producer,
but they're not actually the same role.
The scrum master or the producer is measuring productivity.
They're measuring tasks, how well things get done.
The coaches are very different.
They're looking at how people interact with each other,
how people talk to each other,
how people work with each other.
Oftentimes, people who are naturally inclined to do one
can be inclined to do the other,
but that's not always the case.
So if you have someone on your team
who is one of those extroverted, outgoing,
or even introverted, but really interested
in what individuals do one-on-one
and how individuals work,
see if you can incorporate some coaching strategies
with your teammates.
And again, you can do one-on-one meetings,
and we can talk about this in the future.
If you're interested in this kind of stuff,
we can unpack on this topic and talk about it further.
But I highly recommend it.
All right, so I did mention meetings.
You do have agile meetings.
These people have agile meetings.
These are what they are.
Hopefully you're doing.
So who has a formal sprint process
where you plan your sprint before you start?
So you basically create your sprint task list at a meeting.
Is everyone there?
That's when you're saying, not everyone's there.
We have the tasks, and we hope it's a complete
and final day of the week.
Okay.
So we do have a formal week by week,
but we do go along, it doesn't matter.
Okay, cool.
And you had a meeting to create that.
Okay, so then you have your daily stand-ups
at the end of the sprints.
You wanna have a sprint review,
which is basically the inverse of the sprint planning meeting.
You go back and see what you made.
Hopefully you have a build,
and you just basically look at the build,
compare the build to the completed tasks
and make sure it matches.
The other meeting that you may or may not be doing
is the agile retrospective.
And that's how did you work this week?
Is anybody doing that?
Is anybody at the end of their sprint
talking about, basically talking about the processes
of what you did and how you did it?
Okay, that's kind of what I expect.
I think you're doing yourself a disservice
if you're not doing that.
And in particular, if you are doing that
and you're making that a face-to-face meeting,
that's the time when you can talk about
some of these interpersonal issues.
That's the time when you can talk about your feelings.
That's the time when you can open up
and try to figure out what is about,
like why are some of these tasks not getting taken on?
Who's not doing them?
And what's in their way from doing them?
But really, it's not about the,
it's not really about what's in their way.
It's difficult to talk about.
It's not about what's in their way,
but it might be about what outside of the project
and outside of the team could be in their way.
And you can work through some of those kind of issues.
So, I'm done.
What I'd like you to do before you go
and work in your teams is schedule a sprint retrospective.
So take a look at your sprint process.
How long is your sprint?
Is it one week or two weeks?
We've been assuming it's a one-week process,
one-week sprints.
Schedule a time period that everyone can attend
and a time, an amount of time that they can attend
that they can see each other face-to-face,
but not necessarily are in the same room.
If they can be in the same room, awesome.
If you can't, try to figure out a time that you can chat
using Google Hangout or some other kind of video chat,
some other kind of face-to-face video chat.
Make sure the meeting is focused
on talking about your processes.
So don't talk about your game.
Don't talk about the work that you've done.
Talk about how you organize yourself.
And in particular, talk about your interpersonal matters.
Talk about, basically communicate about communicating.
So talk about how you are talking to each other.
And yeah, I'm gonna talk to you about this again
in a couple of weeks.
And in a couple of weeks, I'm gonna give you some more.
Once you're actually in the process of,
I think most of you right now are probably
in the concepting phase, pre-production phase right now.
You're still kind of figuring out your game.
You haven't quite, like, I guess you guys
are actually working on your back end
because someone did the initial design for you.
The rest are probably still working out that design phase.
When I talk about this again,
you'll likely be in full-on production mode.
And so some of the activities I'm gonna show you
might hopefully help when you're doing these meetings.
Any questions?
Okay, so it's 1.50.
Go ahead and take a few minutes to break.
And then the rest of the class is yours
to work in your teams.
But still, do this.
You can leave it on.
Go ahead.
Oh, my God, this is gonna be so long.
It's gonna be so long.
And actually, I'll turn it off before we move on.
This is a vacation.
Yeah, I don't know.
Yeah, because I love what you have.
I actually think it's gonna be so long.
What's the time?
The time?
I'm not sure.
Yeah, definitely.
So, how about you say it's gonna be so long.
It's gonna be so long.
What's the time?